[music]
>> Coach McCarthy, thank you for [music]
sitting down with us here at the owners
meetings. For you specifically, I mean,
now you've had time to relax and kind of
get settled back into Pittsburgh. How
has it been
driving to work, [music] back home in
Pittsburgh? How has that process been
now? I mean, the drive to work and home
is it's it's incredible. It's something
that
I don't even think you could dream about
it cuz I'm I'm literally driving the
streets that I grew up on. So, you know,
Greenfield Avenue, Second Avenue, across
the bridge, and right down Water Street.
So,
it's still a bit surreal. I'm loving
every minute of it, but it's football. I
mean, there's a lot of work to do. Year
one is is always the hardest year. You
know, I've been through it a couple
times.
>> [music]
>> Been through it a couple times as
assistant. So, really we just have had
our you know, our head down and
just trying to grind and make sure we're
ready to go when the players come back.
Obviously, this time of year, a lot of
guys don't get into the building that
frequently. That'll happen once OTAs
start. But how important is it to kind
of communicate and lean on better than
like a T.J. Watt, a Cam Heyward and
company to kind of impart kind of what
the philosophy and your style is? How is
that process been [music] thus far?
I mean, it's very important. I mean,
this Pittsburgh Steelers has an
incredible
history [music] and tradition. You know,
we're all aware of that, but also it
does have a history of winning
currently. So, and T.J. and Cam are part
of [music] that. You know, I had I had a
really conversations with both men. They
They just want a chance to win it all
before, you know, their career comes to
an end. So, very receptive. They just
want to be part of the messaging, the
new direction. So, [music] basically
both said they coaches tell us tell us
what you want. So, and really everybody
in that locker room currently, that's
who will impact, you know, this upcoming
season. The new players are are very
important. The veterans get them
acclimated. You know, then we got the
rookie class, but these veterans, you
know, they're
They they you know, they know the
Pittsburgh steel way and you know, we're
just taking a little different path. So,
you know, we're we're not trying to
change we're not changing colors. We're
not getting new uniforms. You know, so,
we want to build off all the greatness
that's been here for decades. And
speaking of that, players coming back,
you've added some quality free agents.
And how how did you identify and how was
that process figuring out who those guys
were and to go target and then of course
acquire those players? Yeah, definitely.
I'm I'm big in the play style and in in
physical profile. So, I [music] I think
you see the common thread of everybody
who we signed.
I think it's a great addition to our
roster. So, we don't feel like we have
to go into the draft and say, "Hey, we
need this." We you know, position why we
can really trust our board. We have a
lot of picks.
You know, this is Omar and I's first
draft class together. So,
and and it's I'm a believer in you know,
it's a program shift. Obviously, you
know, Mike said incredible success there
for 19 seasons.
So, we you know, we want this to be a
you know, launching point for for our
new program. Some of those additions, we
talked about the physical profile.
Michael Pittman, obviously. Put him with
D.K. Metcalf. That's That's That's a
That's a dynamic duo. But when you're
talking about that group, it's an
imposing group. And how exciting is it
to have all these kind of big physical
types on the offensive side of the ball?
You played there. I mean, it's it's a
style played the division. It's It's
been that way for since watching them
play in the '70s. So,
>> [snorts]
>> you know, it's it's a style football
that we're going to play. So, Michael,
you know, D.K. We you know, learned it
from last year. We want to move these
guys around. I I think your perimeter
targets, it's important for the [music]
quarterback to be conceptually ingrained
to, you know, his footwork and
understand the concept and the ability
to move your perimeter pieces around to
create matchups. So, you know, and
Michael gives us that flexibility. A lot
of questions have been asked about the
quarterback position. Can you give us
any insights to where we are with Aaron
Rodgers right now? Yes, I mean, Aaron
and I have had continuous dialogue
pretty much every week. So, and we'll
continue to talk. He's, you know,
looking at the [snorts] different things
that that are going on in his life and
I would say he's in a very positive head
space. So, we're we're kind of working
through that and we'll get a decision.
Steelers organization has not gone
through changes very often as as you
very well know.
You know, just kind of talk about this
time of year, the priorities when you're
bringing in a whole new coaching staff,
right? So, you have a lot of new faces
in there. And like you said, veterans
having the different impacts. But how
how is that? What's the priority this
time of year with the new coaching staff
where you guys are at? I mean, the focus
has always been on the draft, player
acquisition, veteran free agency, and
the draft. So, player acquisition and
then scheme implementation. So, that's
really where we're finishing up. Defense
is always a little further ahead than
offense, a little more Like I always
tell defense guys, "We [music] got to
tell you where to line up." So, we we
got a little We got a little more to do.
But
so, we're we're kind of wrapping that up
right now
cuz we we want to be able to get it to
the players through the phase one and
two and and you know, make sure they're
comfortable before we get we all can get
out on the field and and go full speed
[music] in OTAs. That time of year,
getting the guys back in the building
really in in in force with a group of
guys, how important is that time of year
and what are you looking to accomplish
in the OTA period? Anytime you can have
your whole football team together, I
think it's an an important opportunity
that you should try to take advantage
of. So, yeah, when we get to the OTAs,
we'll go to a little different format.
>> [music]
>> We'll spend the first two phases, you
know, teaching everything conceptually.
And then we get to OTAs, we'll do more
installation type, you know, first and
second down and try to exercise more of
a I would call a traditional install
that you know, that we've been been part
of. So, we but we want to get as much
teaching, you know, as much teaching as
we we possibly can throughout those
OTAs. And as the draft comes up, how
involved is the coaching staff in the
draft process given, you know, where
where we're at? How How involved are
they? Very involved. I mean, our coaches
have, you know, we've written a lot of
reports on on a lot of draft picks. So,
I I really like the collaboration
between personnel and coaching.
And I think at the end of the day, it's
it's about getting that board ranked,
you know, getting the board right. And
and then just we just got to have the
discipline trust the board.
And but yeah, I think the collaboration
and and and really I I like the way the
personnel and coaches have been gelling.
Now, draft is in Pittsburgh. Yeah, I'm
with that. Right there right right there
on the three rivers at the confluence of
three rivers as my good buddy Craig
Wolfley used to say. You have 12 picks.
How do you approach your first draft as
a head coach of the Pittsburgh Steelers
knowing you have that type of capital at
your disposal? Patience and discipline.
I've always looked at the draft, you
know, a lot like preparing a game plan
for [music] for the Super Bowl. Just
There's so much work that goes into
that. You spent the whole year. I mean,
you I mean, these scouts have been
banging on these on these guys for
years. You know, the the amount of
information that's collected and the
ability to now bring it together and
you know, let's not forget about the
conversations that took place in,
[music] you know, back in November and
in January. And when we get to the final
grade, let's let's just trust it and
bring them in and then
you can't have you cannot have enough
good football players, Max. That's one
thing I do know about this league.
Absolutely. And happy to have a good one
leading that charge, you coach. Thanks
for Thanks for taking the time to sit
down with us. So, thank you. It's great
visiting with you. All right, appreciate
it.